紫晶
Amethyst.
你能别蹦达了吗？
Do you mind not bouncing so much?
哦
Ooh.
对不起
Sorry.
我只是太兴奋了
I'm just super excited.
葛瑞格要带我去看演出!
Greg is taking me to a show!
演出?
A show?
你指在剧～院那种？
You mean like, at the thee-ay-terr?
不，是摇～滚演出！
No. Like at a Rrrra-ha-hock show!
嘿！要有乐队！在别人家里！
Heh. Like a band! At a house!
还有一大群人
With a whole bunch of people hanging out
一起嗨！
and doing stuff!
噢！天，这听起来酷毙了
Ooh! Man, that sounds cool.
我们晚上也有超棒的计划
We have an awesome night planned, too.
我们在拼拼图
We're doing a puzzle.
哇哦
Wow-wee.
我知道这听起来很逊，但可是612块的
I know it sounds tame, but it has 612 pieces.
并且没有四角！
And no corners!
我发现一块边角
I found a corner.
嘿！
Hey, y'all.
葛瑞格，葛瑞格，葛瑞格，葛瑞格！
Greg, Greg, Greg, Greg!
看来你已经准备好在舞池里嗨了？
So, you ready to throw down in the pit?
我今天晚上去不了了。
No pits for me tonight.
我对不起，紫晶。
I'm sorry, Amethyst.
我完全忘了
It totally slipped my mind
巴尔布邀请我和维达利亚一起打牌
that Barb invited me and Vidalia over for cards.
扑克牌？
Cards?
谁带你们逃出养老院的？
Who broke you guys out of the retirement home?
相信我，我很想去演出的！
Trust me, I'd love to go to the show!
但是巴尔布用我的邮件要挟我
But barb threatened to hold my mail if I didn't.
而且她不是一个空穴来风的女人
And she's not a woman of empty threats.
好吧，算了
Man, forget it.
我去不了演出了
I can't go "show-lo."
真是无聊
That'll be boring.
你今晚可以和我们一起啊
You could hang out with us tonight.
一起拼拼图？呵呵
And do a puzzle? Ha!
也许我们也可以挤点时间织东西
Maybe we can fit in some knitting, too.
我不是指这个
That's not what I meant.
我们可以和你一起去演出
We could go to the show with you.
真的？你确定？
Really? Whaaaa?
你想去演出？
You want to go to a show?
嘈杂的音乐，推搡的人群？
With loud music, and people pushing each other?
我已经完成了公平的互相伤害了
I've done my fair share of pushing.
喔～我觉得胳膊断了
Ohh, I think it's broken.
你们俩从没见过我的另一面！
You two just never saw me in action!
打破每条规矩，反抗权威
Breaking every rule, taking on the authorities,
我就能完全拥抱快乐的地球生活了！
so I could indulge in the joys of life on Earth!
噢！一片天空
Oh! A sky piece.
好
Nice.
当然，你们要去的话可以开我的车
Well, if you'd like to go, you guys can take the Dondai.
谢谢你，葛瑞格
Thank you, Greg.
唔呼！演出！
Whoo-hoo-hoo! Rock show!
等等，珍珠
Hold on, pearl.
这是个人类活动，不是宝石战争
This is a human thing, not a Gem war.
在你嗨翻前，你得先融入其中
Before you rock out, you're gonna want to blend in.
现在你看起来挺拽的了
Now you're looking good.
哦，是的
Oh, yes.
但我可以变得更拽
But I can make it look even gooder.
这很潮，因为领子本来不该这么立着
It's cool, because the collar isn't supposed to go that way.
厉害了我的破
You a natural.
我们快采购玩路上的零食了
We're almost set on snacks for the road.
就差饮料了
We just need some beverages.
草莓糖嗨
Strawberry sugar shock shut down
或者老派苹果汁？
or good old fashioned apple juice?
绝对草莓糖嗨
Definitely sugar shock shut down.
它可以感染任何东西
It turns everything red.
我也来一瓶，史蒂文
I'll have one too, Steven.
我觉得今晚我可以试着喝点东西
I think I'll try drinking tonight.
哇 真的？
Wow, really?
我不知道你喜欢苹果汁啊？
I didn't know you liked apple juice?
我有很多东西你不知道
There's a lot you don't know about me, Steven.
那么，紫晶，介绍下我们要见的乐队
So, Amethyst, tell me more about this band we're seeing.
我们要去见麦克▪克罗
We're going to see Mike Krol.
他懂得真正的车库摇滚氛围
He's got that real garage vibe.
那些怀念市郊的音乐
Songs about being nostalgic for the suburbs.
怀念市郊？切
Nostalgic for the suburbs? Pssh.
它们才存在了大概，70年？
They've only existed for what? 70 years.
好吧，那么，当我们到达现场时
Okay, so, when we get to the show,
得显得这是你的场子
you got to walk in like you own the place.
哦！嘿，看那个！完美的榜样
Oh! Hey, right there. Perfect example.
珍珠，你还好吗？
Pearl, you okay?
呃...
Uh...
我没想到人类也可以有粉发
I just didn't realize humans could come with pink hair.
他们不是真有
They don't.
你要去商店买一种液体
You got to go to the store and get this goo.
闻起来很特效
It smells really bad,
duang的一下头发就有你想要的颜色了
and it turns your hair whatever color you want.
为什么她这么做？
Why would she do that?
你没什么不去问问？
Why don't you go and ask her.
也是！
Hey, yeah!
我们要和许多潮人交往
We're about to go hang out with a bunch of cool humans.
先打把人机！
Go do a practice round!
上！上！上！
Do it! Do it! Do it!
我...呃...
I...uh...
好吧，你向杯子证明了谁是老大
Welp, you sure showed those cups who's boss.
紫晶，安全带
Amethyst, seatbelt.
现在我们该去享受夜晚了
Now let's go have the night of our lives.
我为你燃烧
♪ I'll burn for you,in that way
这样你就可以跟我回家
♪ You can follow me home
好吧，没人要说？
Okay, nobody's gonna say it?
她看起来像妈妈
She kind of looked like mom.
你看出来了。我看出来了。谁都看出来了。
You noticed. I noticed. We all noticed.
难怪你表现得像个呆瓜！
That's why you were acting like such a goon!
不，才不是
No, no. That's not it.
我与过去没有任何关联了
I'm done thinking about the past.
今晚，我只在乎将来
Tonight, I'm all about the future.
我在前往一个演出
I'm going to a show.
我是一个热爱人际关系的新宝石
I'm a new Gem who loves socializing with humans.
只是这样？
That's what that was?
算了，你又不在现场
Look, you weren't there by the cups.
我本可以开口，这都是时辰的错
I could've talked to her. The timing was just wrong.
是那个女孩！她就在旁边！
It's the girl! She's driving right next to us!
不可能！
No way!
人生第二春啊！
You've got another chance!
对！做点什么啊！
Yeah! Do something!
做什么？闪灯？按喇叭？
Like what? Flash my lights? Honk at her?
就给她来个酷炫的转身
Just shoot her a look.
等等
Wait not yet.
好吧...现在！
Okay, okay. You can look...now!
和我所有的朋友拍个照，但清晨我已离开
♪ With all my friends I'll make a picture but in the morning I'll be gone
噢，她走了
Ooh, and there she goes.
嘿，也许她和我们去的一个地方
Hey, maybe she's going to the same show as us.
我不确定，向那么酷的女孩
I don't know, a girl that cool
绝对知道十亿个今天晚上举行的演出
probably knows about a billion shows going on tonight.
珍珠！
Pearl!
啊！
Aaaah!
Yeah, P!
你在干嘛？这是红灯！
What are you doing? The light was red!
我知道
I know.
她在那
There she is.
你有什么计划？
What's your plan?
新珍珠，从不计划
New Pearl. No plan.
呃，真的
Ah, no kidding.
哦
Ooh.
警察来了！
The police want us!
哦天
Oh, snap!
我都干什么了？！
What do I do?!
你要停在路边
You have to pull over to the side
然后出示你的证件
and show them your license.
我没有证件
I don't have a license.
哦，好吧
Oh, right.
但--但你年纪大啊！
But -- But, you're old!
我该告诉车管所什么？
What was I supposed to tell the DMV?
难道我是外星人？
That I'm from another planet?
我都不是公民，史蒂文！
I'm not exactly a citizen, Steven!
那么我们该怎么做？
Then what do we do?
你愿意相信我，回家坐下，顺其自然，即使我自己做不到
♪ Would you believe me and come home and sit back let it be i cant do this by myself
珍珠，你不能直接肇事逃脱！
Pearl, you can't just drive away!
这可是很严肃的
This is serious!
珍珠，你真是个--
Pearl, you're a total bad --
这就是为什么要系安全带
This is why we buckle up.
等等！
Hold on!
天呐撸
Oh, boy.
嘘
Shh.
他们走了吗？
Are they gone?
我觉得是
I think so.
干！
Guh!
怎么了？
What is it?
我们没油了
We're out of gas.
噢，怎么会？
Aw, what?
等等！我去找个加油站
Wait! I'll find a gas station.
看起来最近的...
Looks like the closest one is...
20英里外
20 miles away.
我简直没法相信
I can't believe this.
就差那么点
I was so ready!
我非常想见你说的Krol
I really wanted to see your Krol.
你是指？
What are you talking about?
我本要喝果汁
I was going to drink a juice
和穿这种裤子！
and wear these  pants!
咦～
Ugh!
然后--轻轻的推搡人群
And --  -- hit people gently enough
像你说的，不至于伤害他们那种
as to not actually hurt them, and you'd say,
“哇！珍珠真是酷！”
"Wow! Pearl is really cool!"
但不，相反，我们放着喧嚣的音乐
But no, instead, we drove to loud music,
开着车在半夜追逐那神秘女子
chased a mysterious woman into the night,
还犯了法
and broke the law.
我已经失去理智了
I've lost my edge.
我本应呆在家里拼拼图的
I should have stayed home with the puzzle.
听听你自己
Listen to yourself.
你真是顽固！
You're so hard core!
谁在乎裤子？
Who cares about pants?
你穿着它甩掉了警察！
You gunned it from the cops!
那是自从你差点害死我以来最吓人的时刻（见S01E45）
That's the most scared I've been since you almost let me die!
你现在是个法外狂徒了！
You're a criminal now!
"现在？"
"Now?"
我6000年来一直都是
I've been a criminal for 6,000 years.
等等，你听到了吗？
Wait. Do you hear that?
我们做到了！
We made it!
我像一颗恒星
♪ I'm like a star
我快速的燃烧
♪ I'm burning out fast
我试图闪耀
♪ I try to shine
但不能永存
♪ But it's never gonna last
那个女孩！
And there's the girl.
她真的来这里了
She's actually here.
不可能
No way.
我要去跟她谈谈
I'm going to talk to her.
等等，珍珠
Look, Pearl.
我完全认为你很酷
I already think you're cool.
你可以轻易融入
You can ease into
人类的社交中
the socializing with humans thing.
帮我看着史蒂文
Watch Steven for me.
等等！你不用着急！
Wait, no! You can start smaller!
先试试书呆子啊！
Talk to a nerd!
紫晶
Amethyst.
噢，不！
Aw, no!
喔，她先握手？
Ooh. She's starting with a handshake?
哦，她开始了
Oh, she went for it.
她们都在笑
They're both smiling.
我不敢相信
I can't believe this.
珍珠在说什么？
What is pearl saying?
我不知道，但那个女孩在笑
I don't know, but the girl's laughing.
你觉得是嘲笑还是笑而已？
You think she's laughing at her or with her?
看不出来
Hard to tell.
等等！她回来了！
Shh-shh! She's coming back!
怎么样？
How'd it go?
我问了头发的事
I asked her about her hair,
然后她问我又是怎么染的
and then she asked how I colored mine.
我告诉她，我的外表只是
I told her "My appearance is just
由光刻意制造的
a conscious manifestation of light."
然后她说，“我知道那是什么。”
And she said, "I know how that is."
虽然我不信
Although,  I highly doubt it.
噢，我接着补充，“还有，”
Oh, and then I added, "By the way,
“我挽救了你的星球和种族，”
I saved your planet and your species
“不谢。”
and you're welcome."
最后怎么样？
And how'd that go over?
不是非常好
Not very well.
她给我某种代码后就走了
She walked off after giving me some sort of code.
嘿！
No way!
珍珠，那是电话号码！
Pearl, that's a phone number!
她希望你打给她
She wants you to call her
跟她在电话上聊
and talk to her on the phone!
哦，好吧，我没电话
Oh, well, I don't have a phone.
珍珠！
Pearl!
你刚刚对她就你的光本质莎翁式装b，
You just like gave her some Shakespearean spiel
接着就随随便便拿到号码了！
about light then got her number like it was nothing!
珍珠，你完全是个明星！
Pearl, you're a total rock star!
如果我告诉你世界将毁灭
♪ What if I told you that the world was gonna end? ♪
你只有15分钟陪伴我或者朋友
♪ And you had 15 minutes to spend with me or your friends ♪
你是否愿意
♪ Would you take...
做头班车到我家
♪ The first bus over to my house ♪
或者做末班机去西海岸？
♪ Or would you take the last plane over the West Coast? ♪
像这样的时刻，还有变卦的内心
♪ See, it's times like these with the change of heart ♪
这一切都结束了
♪ It was over and done